Anders Brujordet

Lead Platform Engineer

I started out as a Java consultant focusing on Clean Code and agile methodologies, but I quickly got fascinated by the power and elegance of functional programming with Scala. This lead me to Finn where I got to learn more from a team of excelent scala developers. At Finn I also tried to improve the CI/CI platform and in doing so I got noticed by Schibsted, Finn's parent company. I was hired to be part of the Delivery team in Schibsted to provide a delivery Platform for 1500 developers. When the door to "DevOps" was finally opened many of it's areas caught my interest, and I later joined VPS to help them create a Delivery Platform from scratch while also focusing on improving security.

At home I'm a dad, husband, power lifter, guitarist and hobby tinkerer. The latter might by why DevOps and security resonate so well with me, as I love to take things a part and create new. I've created my own <u>MagicMirror</u> which displays among other things the next train to leave from my local station. I've built, soldered and programmed my own silenced mechanical keyboard which I use every day both at home and at work and when kubernetes was made available I was quick to create my own cluster at home using <u>Raspberry pis and Lego</u>. All my computers and network utilities report metrics and logs using Prometheus, Grafana and Graylog.



Experience

2019 - 2020* CI/CD Platform Lead - Verdipapirsentralen

At VPS I've been attempting to implement a full Delivery Platform for one of Norway's most critical financial institutions. I own the full CI/CD pipelines including code storage, build, code analysis, deployments and engineering productivity. I also contribute in other teams when needed and try to provide general security improvements. Key technologies: Jenkins, OpenShift, Ruby, JavaScript, Java

2016 - 2019 Tech Lead & Senior Software Engineer - Schibsted

I was brought into Schibsted to help create a global Delivery Platform for 1500 developers. My initial role included developing and running Spinnaker for multi cloud deployment pipelines, and utilizing Travis and Artifactory to optimize for speed and resiliency. I was later made the tech lead and technical product owner for CI. The responsibility of the Delivery team was to enable Schibsted's developers to quickly build, test, deploy and manage their services regardless of location, tech stack and cloud provider.

Key technologies: Spinnaker, Travis, Java, Groovy, Python, JavaScript, AWS, Google Cloud and Kubernetes.

2014 - 2016 Senior Developer - Finn.no

I joined Finn to be part of their renowned API team which are know to be excellent Scala developers. I learned a lot from them while developing and maintaining Finn's internal and public API. After a while I started investing more time in their Delivery Platform and especially focusing on the CI/CD part for databases and Varnish cache.

Key technologies: Scala, SBT, python, varnish

2011 - 2014 Java Consultant - Knowit

As a consultant at Knowit it got to work on one of Norway's earliest DevOps driven projects with the Oslo municipality. I also got a taste for the Scala programming language working for Kommuneforlaget, where we created a data warehouse from scratch.

Key technologies: Java, Scala, maven, ruby, Spring, git

2010 - 2011 Java Consultant - SiriusIT

As a engineer in "NAV - Pensjonpgrammet" I took part in development and testing of the governmental letter templating system which was a part of Norway's largest IT project to date.

Key technologies: Java, Scrum, Python

Training

2013 Functional Programming Principles in Scala - Coursera

The class gives an introduction into functional programming in Scala. The class is taught by Martin Odersky, the creator of Scala, and was completed within the given time with a score of "89.6% with distinction".

2010 Oracle Certified Java Programmer 6 - Oracle

The class gives an introduction into functional programming in Scala. The class is taught by Martin Odersky, the creator of Scala, and was completed within the given time with a score of "89.6% with distinction". The official Java Certification was completed with a pass.

Education

2008 - 2010 Master of Computer Science - NTNU

The degree focused on all aspects of data retrieval and storage, resulting in a master thesis on <u>Finding an Optimal Approach for Indexing DNA Sequences</u>

2005 - 2008 Bachelor of Computer Science - NTNU

A broad focus on all aspects of computer science included programming, databases, operating systems, networking data structures and algorithms.

Contact

Address

Vestbybakken 5, 1900 Fetsund, Norway

E-mail

anders@brujordet.no

Blog

blog.brujordet.no

Skills

Backend



Frontend



DevOps

00000

Cloud

00000

Network

00000

Security

••••

Design

••000